qtac.edu.au 2015-04-08

# Privacy_Policy

#### QTAC Information Sheet

Return to Previous Page

#### Queensland Tertiary Admissions Centre (QTAC) Ltd (ABN 28 050 542 633)

Your privacy is important to us and we are committed to handling your personal information in a responsible way in accordance with the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth). This is our Privacy Policy and it sets out how we collect, store, use and disclose your personal information. ** **

**If you do not agree to any of the provisions of this Privacy Policy, you should not use QTAC’s website or services, lodge a QTAC application or provide QTAC with any personal information.** ** **

By visiting the QTAC website, applying for a tertiary place via QTAC or using any of our services or providing us with your information, you agree to your information being collected, held, used and disclosed as set out in this Privacy Policy.

  * information we collect
  * how we collect your information
  * how we use your information
  * how we disclose your information
  * important notice in relation to fraudulent documentation
  * security of your information
  * accuracy, access and correction
  * what to do when you have a complaint
  * revision of our Privacy Policy
  * how to contact us 
  * documents and forms
  * make a privacy enquiry

## The information we collect

Where practicable, we will give you the option of interacting with us anonymously or using a pseudonym. For instance, you do not need to provide any personal information in order to visit the QTAC website and use facilities such as Course Search, nor will you usually be asked to identify yourself if you contact QTAC by telephone with a general enquiry about our services.

We collect the personal information necessary for us to provide you with the services you have requested from us, and to manage your QTAC application. You do not have to provide us with your personal information, but if you do not do so we may not be able to provide you with some or all of our services.

By disclosing personal information to QTAC, you are consenting to its collection by QTAC. If QTAC receives unsolicited personal information about you which it reasonably believes that you have voluntarily disclosed (for instance, if you are listed as the sender on mail containing personal information), this personal information may be included in your QTAC application. This may include personal or sensitive information that QTAC could not have solicited from you. QTAC may choose to destroy unsolicited personal information about you that is not relevant to QTAC's functions. 

The personal information that you are currently required to provide to lodge a QTAC application includes:

  * full name (including any previous name(s))
  * address(es) (including any previous address(es))
  * date of birth
  * email address
  * telephone number(s)
  * qualification information
  * gender
  * citizenship/residency status
  * English proficiency
  * preferences

QTAC also collects information as required by the government, which includes:

  * highest education level of parent(s)/guardian(s)
  * language spoken at home
  * country of birth
  * year of arrival in Australia
  * number and gender of parent(s)/guardian(s)

You also currently have the option of providing other personal information including:

  * current or previous employment details
  * professional certifications and memberships
  * details of an authorised person
  * sensitive information (including health information) in relation to an application under the Educational Access Scheme (EAS) or when seeking special consideration in relation to any of QTAC's services

From time to time you may have the option to participate in surveys or other activities intended to improve QTAC's services, which may involve providing personal information. Your participation in such activities is subject to your consent.

## How we collect your information

We may collect your information in various ways, including:

  * QTAC application and other online services
  * email
  * telephone
  * written correspondence
  * in person
  * private message via Facebook

Whenever possible, QTAC will collect your personal information directly from you. However, in some situations QTAC will collect information that may include your personal information from a third party. These third parties include:

  * institutions, including Secondary institutions, where you have studied or where QTAC reasonably believes you may have studied;
  * Queensland Curriculum and Assessment Authority (QCAA), previously known as Queensland Studies Authority (QSA);
  * Authorities that QTAC reasonably believes may hold results pertinent to your application;
  * Australian Council for Educational Research (ACER);
  * International Baccalaureate Organisation (IBO);
  * Government bodies, departments and agents (including Centrelink and the Department of Education);
  * New Zealand Qualifications Authority (NZQA);
  * Interstate Admission Centres
  * third party verification services, including those located overseas

In addition, by providing the details of an authorised person to QTAC you are consenting to the collection of your personal information from your authorised person. 

On occasion QTAC may ask you to provide the personal information of another person (for example, the Centrelink Customer Reference Number (CRN) for your parent or guardian if you apply under the Educational Access Scheme). By providing this information you are agreeing that you have provided that personal information with the consent of that individual, and that you have let them know about this Privacy Policy and where to find it. We will only use this personal information for the purpose for which it was collected. 

## How we use your information

We only use your personal information for the purpose for which it was provided to us, related purposes and as otherwise required or permitted by law. 

Such purposes include:

  * provision of information about any of QTAC's services that may be relevant to you;
  * provision of information about institution services which may be relevant to you;
  * responding to your enquiries;
  * to identify you when you log into QTAC's online services or otherwise contact QTAC;
  * providing you with services you have requested;
  * processing your QTAC application to determine your eligibility for courses;
  * maintaining/administering your application;
  * processing payments you have authorised; and 
  * any other purposes identified at the time of collecting your information.

We will only use your sensitive information for the purposes for which it was initially collected, other directly related purposes or purposes to which you otherwise consent.

## How we disclose your information

Where appropriate we may disclose your personal information to third parties as required to process your QTAC application or to provide you with other services. The way in which these third parties use your personal information is governed by QTAC's Privacy Policy - Corporate. 

In addition, by providing the details of an authorised person to QTAC, you are consenting to the disclosure of your personal information to your authorised person. 

Your personal information may be disclosed to third parties including:

  * institutions to which you have applied for a tertiary place;
  * institutions, including Secondary institutions, where you have studied or where QTAC reasonably believes you may have studied;
  * Queensland Curriculum and Assessment Authority (QCAA), previously known as Queensland Studies Authority (QSA);
  * Australian Council for Educational Research (ACER);
  * International Baccalaureate Organisation (IBO):
  * mail centres and other similar service providers;
  * Government bodies, departments, agents (including Centrelink and the Department of Education).

On occasion QTAC may disclose your personal information to entities located overseas in order to process your QTAC application or to provide you with other services. You acknowledge that, by agreeing to the disclosure of your information to these entities outside of Australia, QTAC will no longer be required to take reasonable steps to ensure the overseas recipient's compliance with the Australian privacy law in relation to your information and we will not be liable to you for any breach of the Australian privacy law by these overseas recipients and, on this basis, you consent to such disclosure.

We will only disclose your sensitive information for the purposes for which it was initially collected, other directly related purposes, purposes to which you consent, and as otherwise permitted or required by law.

## Important notice in relation to fraudulent documentation

The _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) authorises QTAC to use and disclose your personal information without following the provisions in this Privacy Policy where QTAC has reason to suspect that you have engaged in serious misconduct in relation to QTAC’s functions, if the use or disclosure of the personal information is necessary in order for QTAC to take appropriate action in relation to the misconduct. 

QTAC considers the provision of fraudulent documentation to be serious misconduct in relation to QTAC’s functions. Therefore, if QTAC has reason to suspect that you have presented fraudulent documentation of any kind, QTAC may use or disclose your personal information in a manner inconsistent with this Privacy Policy to the extent required to undertake an investigation into that documentation and to take appropriate action in light of the outcome of the investigation. 

## Security of your information

We will take reasonable steps (including any measures required by law) to ensure your information is protected and secure. 

For any payments you make via our websites, over the telephone or face to face, we use a recognised payment service provider that is required to take reasonable steps to protect your information. We also take reasonable precautions to ensure that any information you provide to us through our websites is transferred securely from our servers to our mainframe computers. 

However, no data protection and security measures are completely secure. Despite all the measures we have put in place, we cannot guarantee the security of your information, particularly in relation to transmissions over the internet. Accordingly, any information which you transmit to us is transmitted at your own risk. You must take care to ensure you protect your information (for example, by protecting your QTAC user names and passwords) and you should notify us as soon as possible after you become aware of any security breaches.

## Accuracy, access and correction

We take reasonable steps to ensure the information we collect and hold about you is accurate, complete and up-to-date. However, we rely on you to advise us of any changes to your information or corrections required to the information we hold about you. You can notify us of a change to your information in the following ways: 

  * telephone: 1300 GO QTAC (1300 467 822)
  * online enquiry: 'Make a privacy enquiry' at the top of this page or via this link: [www.qtac.edu.au/AboutQTAC/QTAC-PrivacyEnquiry.html](http://www.qtac.edu.au/AboutQTAC/QTAC-PrivacyEnquiry.html)
  * in person: Level 4, 154 Melbourne Street, South Brisbane
  * written correspondence: PO Box 1331, Milton, QLD, 4064

QTAC reserves the right to request appropriate supporting evidence/or information to action any request to change your information. 

If you are a current applicant you can update some of your personal information (currently your email, address and telephone) without contacting QTAC. You can do this by logging into the [Current Applicant online service](https://www.qtac.edu.au/oaApps/jsp/aos_entry.jsp). 

In addition, by providing the details of an authorised person to QTAC, you are consenting to the authorised person correcting your personal information. 

QTAC will, upon request, provide you with access to the personal information we hold about you, unless otherwise required or permitted by law. Access to personal information must be made in writing by completing a 'Personal Information Access Request Form', mailed to PO Box 1331, Milton, Queensland, 4064. A service fee may be charged for retrieving and sending the information to you. If you require another means of accessing your personal information QTAC will facilitate this request as long as it is reasonable. 

## What to do if you have a complaint

If you wish to make an enquiry about a possible breach of this Privacy Policy or the privacy principles of the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) or a formal complaint, you can contact us by:

## Enquiry:

  * telephone: 1300 GO QTAC (1300 467 822)
  * online enquiry: 'Make a privacy enquiry' at the top of this page or via this link: [www.qtac.edu.au/AboutQTAC/QTAC-PrivacyEnquiry.html](http://www.qtac.edu.au/AboutQTAC/QTAC-PrivacyEnquiry.html)
  * written correspondence: PO Box 1331, Milton, QLD, 4064

## Formal complaint:

Formal complaints about a breach of this Privacy Policy or the Privacy Principles of the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) must be made in writing by completing a 'Personal Information Breach of Privacy Form', mailed to PO Box 1331, Milton, Queensland, 4064. QTAC reserves the right to request any supporting evidence and/or information to substantiate the complaint/breach.

We will refer your complaint to the responsible officer at QTAC, who will investigate the issue and determine the steps we will undertake to resolve your complaint. We will contact you if we require any additional information from you and will notify you in writing of the determination in relation to your complaint.  

If you are not satisfied with our determination, you can contact us to discuss your concerns or complain to the Australian Privacy Commissioner via [www.oaic.gov.au](http://www.oaic.gov.au/)

## Revision of our Privacy Principle

QTAC reserve the right to revise this Privacy Policy or any part of it from time to time. Please review this policy periodically for changes. If we make significant changes to this policy, we will notify this change by putting a notice on our public website [www.qtac.edu.au](http://www.qtac.edu.au/). 

Your acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy is constituted by your continued use of our services or website, or the provision of further personal or sensitive information to us after this Privacy Policy has been revised.

## How to contact us

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or its implementation, please submit an online enquiry using the 'Make a privacy enquiry' at the top of this page or via this link: [www.qtac.edu.au/AboutQTAC/QTAC-PrivacyEnquiry.html](http://www.qtac.edu.au/AboutQTAC/QTAC-PrivacyEnquiry.html) or call us on 1300 GO QTAC (1300 467 822).

**Documents and Forms**

  * Personal Information Access Request Form
  * Personal Information Breach of Privacy Form

Top of Page
